<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karigiri.net Family Blog</title>
    <description>This blog is to share the thoughts of the Karigiri.net family members. If you are  a member of this family and would like to express your views on anything that you think  would be relevant to other members of the family, please send us your post in an email to hello@karigiri.net  and we shall post it here on your behalf. The site and the blog are bilingual. So, feel free to send us content in either Kannada or English.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.karigiri.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.karigiri.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:37:37 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:37:37 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Possibilities - Now &amp; beyond</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I lay on my bed resting and tending to my sore muscles (due to my overzealous participation at the Swachcha Bharat Abhiyaan by Karigiri.net volunteers), the question that kept creeping up was how to ensure that the family that has been brought together continues to stay connected. Without a driving force or a common cause, most associations tend to weaken over time. We have a website in place and communication channels have been set up (Facebook &amp;amp; Whatsapp). If nothing is done, all these will be relegated to just some forwards/funny messages or the Good Mornings/Good Evenings/Happy Festival kinds of messages. These are necessary, but not sufficient to keep the group alive. Vinay and I had discussed a few ideas on how to utilize the FB/Whatsapp groups. Here are a few of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education Guidance - Courses, Scope,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Career Guidance &amp;amp; Sharing job opportunities - career board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health support (Helping meet blood requirements, doctor suggestions etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keeping communication lines open (Facebook, Whatsapp, E-mail, Newsletters - Monthly, Website updates, Blog posts by members on topics of common interest etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help understand/share information on our culture and traditions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share business opportunities and leads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share a common cause – perform social work/community service as a team – education, health, nature - planting trees etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Annual Family Reunions/Get-togethers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting to know one another.. Birthday, Anniversary wishes etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share photographs from time to time. It will help identify faces and connect them with names.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share old memories, Record songs, bhajans from old members.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on business ideas/startup ideas together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share good deals, vacation ideas, trip experiences and other referrals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know about talented people in our family – musicians, artists etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share family recipes, after all we are Brahmins !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run book reading clubs (remote using Skype)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure, you all will have many more ideas to add to this. It would be great to hear those. Not all of these can be taken up simultaneously, but we should start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more point that was raised during the meeting at Devarayanadurga was establishing a “Fund” to enable certain activities. I also tend to agree with Mari dodappa that the moment we have a “fund” in place, along with it comes the headache of using those funds in a way which should be and seem trustworthy as well to one and all. Many a times, when money is involved, it causes a lot of heartburn and affects the entire family negatively. So, we need a model which can enable us to do things well together while reducing/removing the negativity causing issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I propose:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals come up with “projects” that they wish to lead and make happen. No projects suggestions will be accepted without the willingness of the proposer to lead the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects may range from activities such as tidying up a particular location (cleaning, fencing, painting etc.) to helping a relative tide through health/education related issues and/or expenses among other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to bring the project to reality, it will need more than just the intent. It will generally require money/efforts of people/other resources and overall operational guidance. The most important thing would be garner enough support from people to work with the lead on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could have an online registry of all such “project ideas” and their timelines. The lead will have to study and plan so as to provide an accurate assessment of the cost involved, people support needed etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be other people who’d like to spend some money (however large/small be the amount) on such social activities once in a while. It may be to commemorate events such as a loved one’s birthday, anniversaries, remembering elders and the likes. Such contributors may or may not be able to support projects with their physical efforts but would be willing to financially support part or whole of a project.  People contributing to a project may wish to specify their liking among the projects that are in our online project registry, waiting for execution. In such cases, we could help bridge the finances with the execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volunteers may sign up to support a particular project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as there’s enough support gathered both financially and available volunteers to execute a particular project, we could take up the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every such project, we could assign one of us to be the “Supervisor”. The project lead would be responsible for all purchases and the works while he/she will have to submit proof of all the work done (with receipts where applicable to the assigned supervisor). As a saying goes, locks are there just to keep the honest people, honest. This scheme will enable us to keep the accounts clean and ensure that the benefit of the project reaches the intended target. The team will ensure a detailed accounts of the entire project be kept for viewing by anyone at any time and will ensure absolute transparency. The guiding principle would be to make sure that every rupee of contributed money is spent only on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open to suggestions for tweaks in this and other potential models for collaboration. What do you people think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, we need volunteers from the family to pick either one of the above mentioned tasks or something else they wish to champion. Who’s game?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 18:31:42 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.karigiri.net/2016/05/25/possibilities-now-and-beyond.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.karigiri.net/2016/05/25/possibilities-now-and-beyond.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Karigiri.net journey begins!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first of the “triennial” Karigiri.net was an unequivocal success because of everyone who wholeheartedly participated in the event. For a Monday program, the attendance, which well exceeded 250 people, that too at a place 75 kms away from Bengaluru, was truly amazing and nothing short of a first day first show hit movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People started trickling in early on Sunday (21st) itself. There were a lot of people who hadn’t seen one another ever. Introductions soon resulted in a flow of affection as people started rediscovering their roots and finding interesting people to talk to. It was a true amalgamation of age, experience, knowledge, freshness and energy in one large melting pot. One could clearly see the glimmer of hope and content in the eyes of the seniors to see such strength at display. The young ones were present in great numbers ready to take on the mantle of the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To talk about a Brahmin family gathering and to not mention food would be a sin. So, let’s get it out of the way. 21st afternoon started a series of sumptuous gastronomic delights. The kempu chutney was the best and was clearly the king of the session, while huli, thili saaru and mosaru anna were quite tasty.  Bajji (menasinakayi + one more) &amp;amp; hot coffee were served at 5 in the evening. Dinner that night consisted of chapatis and the usual rice/huli/saaru. The morning of the event, we had soft idlis, kayi chutney, sambar, pongal plus ‘kashi halwa’/’dambrot’. The lunch was extra special consisting of the “Bele Obbattu” + “Bombayi Bonda (aloogedde)” among other things. Delicious kodbales were served during the 3pm meeting. The snack for the evening was the hot “Goli Bajji/Mangaluru Bajji”. Dinner was also extra super, though I had almost no appetite left by then. There were arrangements for the morning breakfast as well the next day, which I had to miss. Coffee was present almost all through the day with some tea and juice being served a couple of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accomodation was arranged at a few places including the “main” chatra + Yatri Nivas and a few other places. Sunday evening was well spent visiting the melina betta along with cousins, uncles and other relatives most of whom I had met after a long time. The conversations continued late into the night until we forced ourselves to our rooms to ensure we got up early in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 6.30am on 23rd Monday, the residents of Devarayanadurga were in for a pleasant surprise. The Karigiri.net volunteers took upon themselves to clean up the vicinity of the temple, the garden and the chatra, in the true spirit of Swachch Bharat Abhiyaan. About 25-30 volunteers, young and old, women &amp;amp; men, cleaned up the main road leading to the chatra and decorated it with mesmerizing Rangoli designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10.30am on 23rd, there were poojes conducted at the temple including “Abhisheka” &amp;amp; the “Utsava” around the garden in the front. Lord Lakshmi Narasimha was welcomed to the “chatra”, which was our temporary home, for a special darshana and pooje. All the family members clearly had a swell time on this joyous occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 3pm, the entire family congregated at the Chatra. The group was addressed by Sri. Lakshminarayana Rao (Mari). He provided an overview of how our family had progressed over the last 8 generations that we are aware of. The elders from 4 of the sub-groups of the Karigirappa family were invited on to the dias and felicitated. It was heartening to hear all these elders speak. More than that, the presence of lots of these elders who made it a point to attend this congregation in spite of their frail health was very inspirational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 5pm, a “family photo” session was conducted near the temple with all of the attendees present. Very soon, we shall be sharing the photographs on our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7.30pm, Belli Rathotsava was conducted within the temple premises. Many of the family members stayed back for this and the ever tasty prasada (dinner) post that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was an experience that was inimitable. So many relationships have been rekindled. People can connect names to faces now and hopefully this spark will only flourish. The hope is to keep this enthusiasm growing and we shall have more wonderful things to report when we all meet again in 3 years. May Lord Lakshmi Narasimha bless one and all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 15:02:01 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.karigiri.net/2016/05/24/karigiri-journey-begins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.karigiri.net/2016/05/24/karigiri-journey-begins.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
